#大家好 今天來兄弟家這個野池塘啊
Hi everyone! Today I come to my buddy's wild pond.
#釣下魚
We come fishing.
#他家的魚都不咬鈎的
But his fish are not biting the hook.
#幸好我把抽水機帶過來了
Fortunately, I am coming with my draining machine.
#等下釣不到我就用抽水機來抽
I'm very ready to use it if I can't catch any fish.
#把它抽乾
Drain the pond!
#好聰明啊 他家的魚
His fish are very clever.
#不釣了
Enough!
#釣不到的
It doesn't work at all.
#這裡都關掉了
Why is it switched off?
#好已抽乾了哦 看下這邊有沒有
So the water is drained. Let's see if there are anything.
#誒 這裡有一條
Eh! Here's a,
#鯽魚
"ji yu" (local carp)
#搞點水
I need some water.
#這個田螺我們也要檢回去
We're taking the river snails as well.
#這回螺
The river snails...
#哇 這裡
Wa! Here,
#這裡
here,
#這裡有一條
here is a fish,
#這回螺我帶回去
and a river snail too.
#這種田螺我也帶回去
This kind of river snails can also be taken.
#這一條 哇
This one, wa!
#哇 哇 這條夠大
Wa! Wa! This is large enough.
#你看
Look!
#這是 這裡有一條
This is, here's another one.
#它們一家人
The whole family,
#大家人都給我帶回去
the whole family will go home with me.
#這田螺
The river snail...
#哇 這裡
Wa! Here,
#這裡有一條
here's one.
#這個鯉魚
This is a carp.
#你看 這裡好多田螺啊
Look! Here are so many river snails.
#你看 我弟他們撿的田螺
Look! These are the river snails picked by our younger brothers.
#這個應該有
There should be,
#三四斤了
around 2 kg.
#全部抓得大的
All are large ones.
#這一種小魚
This is a small fish.
#這還有一條魚 (註︰這句和上一句其實不知他說甚麼)
Here's a fish too.
#我把這個魚搞出來看一看
Let me pour out the fish and have a look.
#看一下今天的收獲有多少
See how much we have today.
#應該四五斤這個
It should be almost two and a half kilogram.
#五斤 五斤就有
Yup, two and a half, two and a half.
#好啦
Alright!
#今天的視頻就到這裡了
The video ends here.
#天都快黑了 黑盡快回去
It's getting dark now. We need to head back as soon as possible.
#今天晚上我們就把它煮啦
They will be our dinner tonight.
#這下面還有好多小魚我都沒抓
There are still a lot of small fish down there.
#把水放回去
Release the water back to the pond!
#這裡稍微堵一下 (註︰完全不明白，他是把石推走的)
Let's put the rocks here.
#好啦 我們回去啦
Alright! Let's go!